A Guide to the Philip S. Hench Walter Reed Yellow Fever Collection 1806-1995
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- THE YELLOW FEVER ROLL OF HONOR, CHRONOLOGY OF THE YELLOW FEVER WORK IN CUBA 1899 AND 1900 1928/02/16, TMs, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 031-043)
- LETTER FROM O. BINLEY TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1928/02/17, ALS (Box-folder 031-044)
- LETTER FROM SIDNEY COE HOWARD TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1928/02/21, TLS (Box-folder 031-045)
  WITH ENVELOPE RE HIS PLAY ABOUT WALTER REED
- HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES BILL NOS. 3364, 11686 "1928/02/24, 03/02", DOCUMENT, DOCUMENTS (P) (2) (Box-folder 031-046)
  TO PROVIDE FOR THE PLACING OF THE NAMES OF CERTAIN INDIVIDUALS OF THE ROLLS OF THE WAR DEPARTMENT, AND TO AUTHORIZE THE BOARD OF REGENTS OF THE SMITHSONIAN INSTITUTION TO MAKE CERTAIN RECOMMENDATIONS
- SPEECH OF HON. EDWARD T. TAYLOR TO THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES 1928/03/01, REPORT (Box-folder 031-047)
- LETTER FROM MARIE C. OEMLER TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1928/03/04, TLS (Box-folder 031-048)
- THE REPUBLIC REMEMBERS BY JAMES E. PEABODY 1928/03, PAMPHLETS (2), PAMPHLET (P) (Box-folder 031-049)
- LETTER FROM WINFIELD SCOTT TO HOWARD A. KELLY 1928/04/09, TLS (Box-folder 031-050)
- HEARING BEFORE THE COMMITTEE ON MILITARY AFFAIRS, HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES 1928/04/11, REPORT (Box-folder 031-051)
  RE YELLOW FEVER
- HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES BILL NO. 13060, REPORT NO. 1429 1928/04/14, DOCUMENT, DOCUMENT (P), REPORT, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 031-052)
  TO RECOGNIZE THE HIGH PUBLIC SERVICE RENDERED BY MAJOR WALTER REED AND THOSE ASSOCIATED WITH HIM IN THE DISCOVERY OF THE CAUSE AND MEANS OF TRANSMISSION OF YELLOW FEVER
- EASTER SUNDAY SUNRISE SERVICE, WALTER REED HOSPITAL GROUNDS 1928/04/15, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 031-053)
  THE SUNDAY STAR (WASHINGTON D.C.)
- LETTER FROM HOWARD A. KELLY TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1928/05/12, TLS (Box-folder 031-054)
- EXTENSION OF REMARKS OF HON. SCHUYLER O. BLAND ON WALTER REED 1928/05/18, JOURNAL CLIPPING (Box-folder 031-055)
  CONGRESSIONAL RECORD
- LETTER FROM SIMON FLEXNER TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1928/05/28, TLS (Box-folder 031-056)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM C. BORDEN TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1928/05/29, ALS (Box-folder 031-057)
- PRIVATE DEAN--APOTHEOSIS OF COURAGE 1928/08/26, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 031-058)
- LETTER FROM JAMES E. PEABODY TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1928/08/29, ALS (Box-folder 031-059)
- LETER FROM JOHN J. PERSHING TO EDWIN F. SWEET 1928/09/06, TLS (P) (Box-folder 031-060)
  RE PRIVATE WILLIAM H. DEAN
- LETTER FROM JAMES E. PEABODY TO ALVAH H. DOTY 1928/09/09, TLS (CC) (Box-folder 031-061)
- LETTER FROM [JAMES E. PEABODY] TO JOHN J. MORAN 1928/1015, TL (P) (Box-folder 031-062)
- LETTER FROM FREDERICK J. COVILLE TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1928/10/22, TLS (Box-folder 031-063)
- LETTER FROM MERRITTE W. IRELAND TO JAMES E. PEABODY 1928/11/16, TLS (P) (Box-folder 031-064)
- LETTER FROM JAMES E. PEABODY TO HOWARD A. KELLY 1928/11/26, TLS (Box-folder 031-065)
- LETTER FROM CLARENCE P. JONES TO HOWARD A. KELLY 1928/12/10, TLS (Box-folder 031-066)
- BOOK REVIEW--YELLOW FEVER: AN EPIDEMIOLOGICAL AND HISTORICAL STUDY OF ITS PLACE AND ORIGIN BY HENRY ROSE CARTER (EDITED BY WADE HAMPTON FROST AND LAURA ARMISTEAD CARTER) 1928, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 031-067)
- REPORT OF PROGRESS TO DISCHARGING OUR NATION'S DEBT OF HONOR TO THOSE YELLOW FEVER HEROES OF 1900 1928, REPORTS (2) (Box-folder 031-068)
- FULTON BRIDGE WILL BE NAMED SUNDAY AFTER PRIVATE WILLIAM H. DEAN 1928, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (P) (Box-folder 031-069)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM T. DAVIS TO WILLIAM C. BORDEN 1929/01/07, TLS (Box-folder 031-070)
- THE ROMANCE OF MEDICAL MARTYRDOM 1929/01/13, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 031-071)
- WHY WALTER REED HOSPITAL WAS NAMED AND LOCATED AS IT IS. AN ADDRESS TO STUDENT NURSES BY P.M. ASHBURN 1929/02/04/ca., TMs (CC) (Box-folder 031-072)
- YELLOW FEVER ROLL OF HONOR, HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES NO. 2720 1929/02, REPORTS (2), REPORT (P) (Box-folder 031-073)
- INADEQUATE SERVICE WIDOWS' PENSIONS 1929/03/07, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 031-074)
  ARMY AND NAVY REGISTER
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM A. TANSEY TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED "1929/03/10, 05/01", ALS (2) (Box-folder 031-075)
- LETTER FROM C.H. BRIDGES TO GUSTAF E. LAMBERT 1929/03/21, TL (P) (Box-folder 031-076)
- LETTER FROM C.C. FLETCHER TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/04/03, TLS (Box-folder 031-077)
- GENTLEMEN, I SALUTE YOU! 1929/04/13, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 031-078)
  SATURDAY EVENING POST
- RE: YELLOW FEVER RESEARCH -- GORGAS, REED, JENKINS, ET AL. "1912, 1913, 1918", 3-NEWSCLIPPINGS (Box-folder 031-078)
  FROM BALTIMORE AMERICAN AND NEW YORK TRIBUNE
- TELEGRAMS FROM W.A. O'CONNELL, R.C. THOMPSON TO JOHN J. MORAN "1929/04/15, 05/03", TELEGRAMS (2) (Box-folder 031-079)
  CONGRATULATIONS RE: WINNING CONGRESSIONAL MEDAL OF HONOR
- REAL HEROISM 1929/04/19, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (P) (Box-folder 031-080)
  THE MIAMI HEARLD RE JOHN J. MORAN
- DRAMA OF MEDICINE'S CONQUEST OVER YELLOW FEVER DEPICTED FOR DOCTORS OF STATE BY RETIRING HEAD DR. E. TERRY SMITH 1929/05/04, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (P) (Box-folder 031-081)
  THE HARTFORD DAILY TIMES
- LETTER FROM LYTTON G. AMENT TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/05/10, TLS (Box-folder 031-082)
- LETTER FROM MORRIS SHEPPARD TO JESSE DANIEL AMES 1929/05/16, TL (Box-folder 031-083)
- WAR DEPARTMENT NEWS RELEASE: ADDRESS OF SECRETARY OF WAR, HONORABLE JAMES W. GOOD, TO THE GRADUATING CLASS OF THE U.S. MILITARY ACADEMY, WEST POINT 1929/06/13, TMs (Box-folder 031-084)
- LETTER FROM JEFFERSON RANDOLPH KEAN TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED "1929/06/17, 20", ALS (Box-folder 031-085)
- LETTER FROM JOHN J. MORAN TO JAMES E. PEABODY 1929/07/07, TLS (P), TL (Box-folder 032-001)
  WITH BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH OF MORAN
- LETTER FROM FREDERICK F. RUSSELL TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/07/08, TLS (Box-folder 032-002)
- LETTER FROM MERRITTE W. IRELAND TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/07/23, TLS (Box-folder 032-003)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM G. HARRISON TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED "1929/08/10, 24", ALS, TLS (Box-folder 032-004)
- LETTER FROM JEFFERSON RANDOLPH KEAN TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/08/14, TLS (Box-folder 032-005)
- LETTER FROM ELIZABETH L. IRELAND TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/08/22, ALS (Box-folder 032-006)
- ROLL OF HONOR, WITH BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCHES 1929/08/27, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 032-007)
- LETTER FROM FREDERICK V. COVILLE TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/08/30, TLS (Box-folder 032-008)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM G. HARRISON TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/09/10, ALS (Box-folder 032-009)
- LETTER FROM LANDON REED TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED, AND TO BLOSSOM [EMILIE M.] REED 1929/09/14, ALS (2) (Box-folder 032-010)
  BOTH IN 1 ENVELOPE
- LETTER FROM W.S. LEATHERS TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/09/30, TLS (Box-folder 032-011)
- LETTER FROM RICHARD M. HEWITT TO EDITOR, NEW ORLEANS MEDICAL AND SURGICAL JOURNAL 1929/09, TL (CC) (Box-folder 032-012)
- LETTER FROM S.F. BLAKE TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/10/22, TLS (Box-folder 032-013)
- INTERVIEW WITH SURGEON GENERAL MERRITTE W. IRELAND 1929/10/22, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 032-014)
- WILLIAM B. OLSEN AWARDED CONGRESSIONAL GOLD MEDAL 1929/10/09/ca., NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 032-015)
  CHICAGO TRIBUNE
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM A. TANSEY TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/11/04, AENVELOPE, PHOTOGRAPHS (4) (Box-folder 032-016)
  CONTAINS 4 PHOTOGRAPHS
- LETTER FROM [JAMES E. PEABODY] TO JONATHAN MAYHEW WAINWRIGHT 1929/11/18, TL (CC) (Box-folder 032-017)
- LETTER FROM C.H. BRIDGES TO JESSE DANIEL AMES 1929/11/19, TL (CC) (Box-folder 032-018)
- LETTER FROM MERRITTE W. IRELAND TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1929/12/02, TLS (Box-folder 032-019)
- LETTER FROM [LAURA ARMISTEAD CARTER] TO FREDERICK F. RUSSELL 1929/12/16, TL (CC) (Box-folder 032-020)
- LETTER FROM [JAMES E. PEABODY] TO GEORGE KELLOGG 1929/12/18, TL (CC) (Box-folder 032-021)
- LETTER FROM [JAMES E. PEABODY] TO CLARA, RICHARD, AND GEORGE PEABODY 1929/12/29, TL (CC) (Box-folder 032-022)
- IN RECOGNITION OF A GREAT ACHIEVEMENT 1929/12/30, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 032-023)
- NATIONAL HONORS FOR THE YELLOW FEVER HEROES 1929, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 032-024)
- ENVELOPE WHICH CONTAINED CHARTS OF EXPERIMENTAL YELLOW FEVER CASES 1929, AENVELOPE (Box-folder 032-025)
  WITH ANNOTATIONS BY ROGER POST AMES
- LETTER FROM BILLIE [s.n.] TO MRS. PEGGY LAZEAR BRIGGS 1929/ca., ALS (Box-folder 032-026)
- WIDOW OF VICTOR OVER YELLOW FEVER GETS $1500 PENSION 1930/01/02, NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (P) (2) (Box-folder 032-027)
- LETTER FROM JAMES E. PEABODY TO JOHN J. MORAN 1930/01/08, TL (P) (Box-folder 032-028)
- LETTER FROM DOROTHY BLONDEL TO JOHN J. MORAN 1930/01/13, TLS (Box-folder 032-029)
- LETTER FROM PATRICK J. HURLEY TO MORRIS SHEPPARD 1930/01/29, TL (CC) (Box-folder 032-030)
- LETTER FROM [MORRIS SHEPPARD] TO PATRICK J. HURLEY 1930/01/31, TL (CC) (Box-folder 032-031)
- LETTER FROM MORRIS SHEPPARD TO JESSIE DANIEL AMES 1930/01/31, TL (CC) (Box-folder 032-032)
- LETTER FROM PATRICK J. HURLEY TO MORRIS SHEPPARD 1930/02/08, TL copy (Box-folder 032-033)
- LETTER FROM MORRIS SHEPPARD TO JESSE DANIEL AMES 1930/02/11, TL (CC) (2) (Box-folder 032-034)
  ENCLOSES COPY OF 1930/02/08 LETTER FROM PATRICK J. HURLEY TO MORRIS SHEPPARD
- LETTER FROM C.H. BRIDGES TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1930/03/05, TLS (Box-folder 032-035)
- HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES REPORT NO. 841: HONOR THE MEMORY OF THE HEROES OF THE FIGHT AGAINST YELLOW FEVER 1930/03/05, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 032-036)
- THE MARTYRS OF MEDICAL SCIENCE 1930/03/30, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 032-037)
- NOTEBOOK AND NOTE CARDS 1930/03-08, AMs (Box-folder 032-038)
- HISTORY OF YELLOW FEVER: NOTES FOR M.J. ROSENAU PROBABLY BY HENRY ROSE CARTER N.D., MOVED TO BOX 012 FOLDER 014 (Box-folder 032-039)
  MISCATALOGUED, MOVED TO BOX 012 FOLDER 014
- LETTER FROM MARGARET H. LOWER TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1930/04/08, TLS, PROGRAM (Box-folder 032-040)
  1 PAGE WITH ENVELOPE WITH PROGRAM FOR BREAKING GROUND FOR THE MEMORIAL CHAPEL, WALTER REED HOSPITAL
- LETTER FROM ARISTIDES AGRAMONTE TO JESSIE DANIEL AMES 1930/05/27, TL (CC) (Box-folder 032-041)
- A CUBAN PATRIOT WHO FOUGHT A PLAGUE BY S.J. WOOLF 1930/06/08, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (P) (Box-folder 032-042)
  THE NEW YORK TIMES MAGAZINE RE ARISTIDES AGRAMONTE
- MEMORANDUM--ACKNOWLEDGMENTS 1930/08/24, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 032-043)
- LETTER FROM [LAWRENCE T. ROYSTER] TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1930/11/15, ALS (Box-folder 032-044)
- LETTER FROM MARGARET H. LOWER TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1930/12/11, TLS (Box-folder 032-045)
- LETTER FROM MERRITTE W. IRELAND TO WILLIAM R. SMITH 1930/12/12, TL (P) (Box-folder 032-046)
- LETTER FROM LAWRENCE T. ROYSTER TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1930/12/24, TLS (Box-folder 032-047)
- FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO [ ] n.d. [1930/12?], A CHRISTMAS CARD (Box-folder 032-048)
- STATEMENT WRITTEN BY DR. L.O. HOWARD 1930, TMs, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 032-049)
  RE HIS ROLE IN YELLOW FEVER ERADICATION
- EXCERPT FROM A HISTORY OF APPLIED ENTOMOLOGY BY L.O. HOWARD 1930, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 032-050)
- 2 POEMS: HOW IT HAPPENED AND ELLIOTT HOLMAN SENT TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1931/01/20, TMs (Box-folder 032-051)
  IN ENVELOPE ADDRESSED TO MRS. WALTER REED
- LETTER FROM HELEN CRANE NOLTE TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1931/02/14, ALS (Box-folder 032-052)
- LETTER FROM EDWIN ANDERSON ALDERMAN TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1931/02/18, TLS (Box-folder 032-053)
- LETTER FROM GERTRUDE B. UPDEGRAFF TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1931/03/07, ALS (Box-folder 032-054)
- LETTER FROM WILBURT C. DAVIDSON TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED "1931/03/09, 16", TLS (2) (Box-folder 032-055)
- A BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH OF WALTER REED BY B. EDWARD VEDDER 1931/04/06, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 032-056)
- PHOTO OF GATHERING FOR SUNRISE SERVICE ON THE GROUNDS OF WALTER REED HOSPITAL 1931/04/12, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 032-057)
- MERRITTE W. IRELAND TO ALBERT E. TRUBY 1931/08/21, ALS (Box-folder 032-058)
- WALTER REED HOSPITAL 1931/08, MAGAZINE CLIPPING (Box-folder 032-059)
  AMERICAN MOTORIST
- OBITUARY NOTICE FOR ARISTIDES AGRAMONTE 1931/08, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (P) (Box-folder 032-060)
- FROM FEVER SWAMPS TO IMMORTALITY 1931/09/13, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 032-061)
  THE WASHINGTON POST RE: 80TH ANNIVERSARY OF WALTER REED'S BIRTH
- CORRESPONDENCE BETWEEN EMILIE L. REED TO HERBERT S. HOLLANDER 1931/09, ALS, TLS (Box-folder 032-062)
- LETTER FROM OREN BRITT BROWN TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1931/10/06, ALS (Box-folder 032-063)
- LETTER FROM SIDNEY COE HOWARD TO ALBERT E. TRUBY "1931/12/07, 19", TLS (2) (Box-folder 032-064)
- LETTER FROM SIDNEY COE HOWARD TO JOHN J. MORAN 1931/12/22, TLS, TLS (P) (Box-folder 032-065)
- SPEECH TO BE GIVEN AT INAUGURATION OF TABLET TO JESSE W. LAZEAR AT COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY 1931, TMs (P) (Box-folder 032-066)
  [PROBABLY NOT DELIVERED]
- NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS AND PHOTOGRAPHS OF WALTER REED HOSPITAL 1931, *NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (Box-folder 032-067)
- NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS RE: WALTER REED 1931/ca., *NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (Box-folder 032-068)
- LETTER FROM SIDNEY COE HOWARD TO JOHN J. MORAN 1932/01/12, TLS (Box-folder 032-069)
- LETTER FROM SIDNEY COE HOWARD TO JOHN J. MORAN "1932/01/18, 22", TELEGRAMS (2) (Box-folder 032-070)
- LETTER FROM SIDNEY COE HOWARD TO JOHN J. MORAN 1932/02/04, TLS (Box-folder 032-071)
- MEMORANDUM FROM ALBERT E. TRUBY TO SURGEON GENERAL 1932/03/09, TMEMO (CC) (Box-folder 032-072)
- DRAFT OF LETTER FROM SECRETARY OF WAR TO DAVID A. REED 1932/03/18, TL (CC) (Box-folder 032-073)
- ROLL OF HONOR, YELLOW FEVER VOLUNTEERS 1932/05/07, PAMPHLET, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 032-074)
- LETTER FROM RICHARD B. RITCHEY TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1932/06/26, ALS, TMs (Box-folder 032-075)
  1 PAGE WITH ENVELOPE ENCLOSING COPY OF 'UNSUNG HEROES'
- LETTER FROM P.R. HAWLEY TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1932/10/06, TLS (Box-folder 032-076)
- LETTER FROM JAMES E. PEABODY TO CAROLINE LATIMER 1932/10/21, TL (P), PHOTOGRAPHS (2) (Box-folder 032-077)
  WITH PHOTOGRAPHS OF [WARREN] JERNEGAN'S GRAVE
- HEALTH HEROES: ROBERT KOCH 1932, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 032-078)
- LETTER FROM SIDNEY COE HOWARD TO JOHN J. MORAN 1933/01/12, TLS, TLS (P) (Box-folder 033-001)
- LETTER FROM FREDERICK F. RUSSELL TO ALBERT E. TRUBY 1933/01/17, TLS (Box-folder 033-002)
- LETTER FROM ALBERT E. TRUBY TO FREDERICK F. RUSSELL 1933/02/25, TL (CC) (Box-folder 033-003)
- LETTER FROM JAMES C. REED TO JAMES E. PEABODY 1933/06/20-ca. 1943, TL (CC) (4) (Box-folder 033-004)
  WITH COPIES OF 1941/12/10 LETTER FROM LAURA WOOD TO JAMES E. PEABODY AND 1942/02/02 LETTER FROM SIMON FLEXNER TO JAMES E. PEABODY
- LETTER FROM JOHN D. SCHWIEGER TO ALBERT E. TRUBY 1933/06/21, ALS (Box-folder 033-005)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM F. KING TO JOHN J. MORAN 1933/06/22, TLS (Box-folder 033-006)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM F. KING TO JOHN J. MORAN 1933/08/10, TLS (Box-folder 033-007)
- EL LIBRO DE LA VICTORIA 1933-1935/04, PROGRAM (Box-folder 033-008)
- LETTER FROM JOHN J. MORAN TO WILLIAM F. KING 1933/09/07, CABLEGRAM (Box-folder 033-009)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM F. KING TO JOHN J. MORAN 1933/10/17, TLS, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 033-010)
  WITH PROGRAM OF MEMORIAL SESSION AND BANQUET HONORING WALTER REED AND THOSE ASSOCIATED WITH HIM
- CENTENTAIRE DU DOCTEUR CARLOS J. FINLAY 1933/12/05, REPORT (Box-folder 033-011)
  IN FRENCH
- MAJOR GENERAL WILLIAM CRAWFORD GORGAS, M.C., U.S.A. BY FRANKLIN MARTIN 1933, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 033-012)
- WALTER REED IN RIPLEY'S BELIEVE IT OR NOT 1933, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 033-013)
- HEALTH THROUGH THE AGES 1933, PAMPHLETS (2) (Box-folder 033-014)
- LETTER FROM SIDNEY COE HOWARD TO JOHN J. MORAN 1934/03/06, TLS, TLS (P) (Box-folder 033-015)
- REVIEW OF 'YELLOW JACK' BY SIDNEY COE HOWARD 1934/03/19, MAGAZINE CLIPPING (Box-folder 033-016)
  TIME MAGAZINE
- LETTER FROM ROBERT V. PATTERSON TO JOHN J. MORAN 1934/06/13, TLS (Box-folder 033-017)
- LETTER FROM WALTER DE BLOIS BRIGGS TO SIDNEY COE HOWARD 1934/07/23, TL (CC), TL (P) (Box-folder 033-018)
- ROOSEVELT IN HAWAII 1934/07/24-28, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 033-019)
- AMERICAN EXPLORER 1934/07, JOURNAL (Box-folder 033-020)
- LETTER FROM SIDNEY COE HOWARD TO WALTER DE BLOIS BRIGGS 1934/08/11, TLS, TLS (P) (Box-folder 033-021)
- STATEMENT OF WINIFRED E. LEWIS WHO NURSED DR. ROGER POST AMES AT THE YELLOW FEVER HOSPITAL 1934/10/13, TMs (P) (Box-folder 033-022)
- RECOLLECTIONS OF PERSONAL EXPERIENCES IN CONNECTION WITH YELLOW FEVER EPIDEMICS IN HAVANA 1898-1899-1900 BY CHAUNCEY B. BAKER 1935/11/05, TMs, TMs (CC) (2) (Box-folder 033-023)
- A CENTURY OF METHODISM IN CHARLOTTESVILLE, VIRGINIA 1934/11/11-14, PROGRAM 2 COPIES (Box-folder 033-024)
  ONE WITH AN AUTOGRAPH BY ATCHESON HENCH
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM T. DAVIS TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1934/12/22, TLS (Box-folder 033-025)
- LETTER FROM CHAUNCEY B. BAKER TO ALBERT E. TRUBY 1935/01/17, TLS (Box-folder 033-026)
- SENATE BILL S. 1850 1935/02/14, DOCUMENT (P) (Box-folder 033-027)
  TO AMEND AN ACT ENTITLED 'AN ACT TO RECOGNIZE THE HIGH PUBLIC SERVICE RENDERED BY MAJOR WALTER REED AND THOSE ASSOCIATED WITH HIM IN THE DISCOVERY OF THE CAUSE AND MEANS OF TRANSMISSION OF YELLOW FEVER'
- LETTER FROM J.G. WOODS TO JAMES E. PEABODY 1935/02/16, TL (CC) (5) (Box-folder 033-028)
  ENCLOSING COPIES OF LETTERS OF THEODORE ROOSEVELT AND HENRY CABOT LODGE
- LETTER FROM SIDNEY COE HOWARD TO JOHN J. MORAN 1935/02/20, TLS (Box-folder 033-029)
- LETTER FROM ESTELA AGRAMONTE RODRIGUEZ LEON TO JAMES E. PEABODY 1935/03/12, TL (CC) (Box-folder 033-030)
- CORRESPONDENCE BETWEEN CHAUNCEY B. BAKER AND ALBERT E. TRUBY "1935/04/03, 13", TL (CC), TLS (Box-folder 033-031)
- LETTERS FROM S.S. GOLDWATER TO ALBERT E. TRUBY 1935/05/04, TL (CC) (Box-folder 033-032)
  ENCLOSING TL (CC) (5) 1935/04/06-05/01 (CORRESPONDENCE OF S.S. GOLDWATER)
- LETTER FROM JAMES E. PEABODY TO NEW YORK ASSOCIATION OF BIOLOGY TEACHERS 1935/05/05, TL (CC) (Box-folder 033-033)
- THE MOST HISTORIC CITY IN THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA 1935/06/22, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 033-034)
  THE WAR CRY MENTIONS WALTER REED
- LETTER FROM JOHN H. ANDRUS TO DONALD H. MACLEAN 1935/07/19, TL (CC) (2), TL (P) (Box-folder 033-035)
- BIOGRAPHERS TURN SLEUTH, TRACKING DOWN NEW FACTS ABOUT THE FAMOUS 1935/07/21, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 033-036)
  THE WASHINGTON POST RE: WALTER REED
- THE HARRISBURG CHURCHMAN 1935/07, NEWSLETTER (Box-folder 033-037)
- LETTER FROM JOHN H. ANDRUS TO JAMES H. LEWIS 1935/08/09, TLS (CC) (Box-folder 033-038)
- MEMOIR OF REV. JAMES C. REED [BROTHER OF WALTER REED] 1935/10/16-21, PROGRAM (P) (Box-folder 033-039)
  THE VIRGINIA CONFERENCE ANNUAL
- LETTER FROM JAMES E. PEABODY TO JOHN J. MORAN 1935/12/10, TLS (Box-folder 033-040)
- MEMORANDUM FROM FRANK T. HINES TO COLONEL IJAMS 1935/12/20, TMEMOS, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 033-041)
  WITH 'WALTER REED: A MEMOIR' DELIVERED BY WESLEY C. COX
- LETTER FROM EDWARD ANGLES TO JAMES E. PEABODY 1935/12/27, TL (P) (Box-folder 033-042)
  WITH PHOTOGRAPHS OF YELLOW FEVER CAMP
- LETTER FROM WILBUR A. SAWYER TO ALBERT E. TRUBY 1936/01/-2, TLS (Box-folder 033-043)
- OBITUARY NOTICES FOR LEVI E. FOLK 1936/01/10, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (P) (Box-folder 033-044)
- LETTER FROM WILBUR A. SAWYER TO ALBERT E. TRUBY 1936/02/02, TLS (Box-folder 033-045)
- OBITUARY NOTICES FOR LEVI E. FOLK 1936/02/09-10, NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (2), NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (P) (Box-folder 033-046)
- 'ELIZABETH' 1866 1936/06/08, JOURNAL CLIPPING (Box-folder 033-047)
  AUTHORS TODAY AND YESTERDAY WITH ENVELOPE ADDRESSED TO MRS. WALTER REED
- LETTER FROM ALLEN R. BOYD TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1936/07/10, TLS (Box-folder 033-048)
- LETTER FRAGMENT TO ALBERT E. TRUBY 1936/07/15, TL (Box-folder 033-049)
- LETTER FROM N. PAUL HUDSON TO EMILIE LAWRENCE REED 1936/11/05, TLS, PROGRAM (Box-folder 033-050)
  WITH ENVELOPE AND PROGRAM OF THE 32ND ANNUAL MEETING OF THE AMERICAN SOCIETY OF TROPICAL MEDICINE
- THE WALTER REED MEDAL 1936, ARTIFACT (Box-folder 033-051)
  AWARDED BY THE AMERICAN SOCIETY OF TROPICAL MEDICINE TO MRS. WALTER REED IN RECOGNITION OF MERITORIOUS ACHIEVEMENT IN TROPICAL MEDICINE BRASS IN CASE
- RADIO PROGRAM: THE HEROES OF THE YELLOW FEVER EXPERIMENTS IN CUBA IN 1900 1937/01/10, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 034-001)
- LETTER FROM JOHN H. ANDRUS TO JOHN J. MORAN 1937/01/14, TLS (Box-folder 034-002)
- LETTER FROM F.N. RAYMOND TO JOHN J. MORAN 1937/01/19, TLS (Box-folder 034-003)
- LETTER FROM RALPH COOPER HUTCH[ISON TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1937/02/01, TLS (Box-folder 034-004)
- LETTER FROM [s.n.] ROVENSKY TO RALPH COOPER HUTCHISON 1937/02/03, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-005)
- LETTER FROM LORD DAWSON TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1937/02/12, TLS (Box-folder 034-006)
- LETTER FROM LORD DAWSON TO RALPH COOPER HUTCHISON 1937/02/13, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-007)
  ENCLOSED WITH LETTER OF DAWSON TO HENCH 1937/02/12 034/006
- LETTER FROM RALPH COOPER HUTCH[ISON TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1937/02/16, TLS (Box-folder 034-008)
- LETTER FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO RALPH COOPER HUTCHISON 1937/02/22, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-009)
- OBITUARY NOTICES FOR CHARLES G. SONNTAG 1937/02/22-25, NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (3) (Box-folder 034-010)
- LETTER FROM RALPH COOPER HUTCHISON TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH "1937/03/04, 08", TLS (2) (Box-folder 034-011)
- LETTER FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO RALPH HUTCHISON, LORD DAWSON 1937/04/05, TL (CC) (2) (Box-folder 034-012)
- LETTER FROM JOHN J. MORAN TO ALBERT E. TRUBY 1937/04/27, TLS (Box-folder 034-013)
- RADIO PROGRAM: THE HEROES OF THE YELLOW FEVER EXPERIMENTS IN CUBA, JUNE TO DECEMBER 1900 1937/05/15, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 034-014)
- LETTER FROM JOHN H. ANDRUS TO GUSTAF E. LAMBERT 1937/05/18, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-015)
- JOHN H. ANDRUS TO GUSTAF E. LAMBERT 1937/06/16, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-016)
- LETTER FROM [JOHN H. ANDRUS] TO JOHN D. SCHWEIGER 1937/07/01, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-017)
- LETTER FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO GOVERNMENT PRINTING OFFICE 1937/07/06, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-018)
- LETTER FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO JOHN J. MORAN 1937/07/06, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-019)
- LETTER FROM GUSTAF E. LAMBERT TO JESSIE DANIEL AMES 1937/07/11, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-020)
- LETTER FROM JOHN J. MORAN TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1937/07/18, TLS (Box-folder 034-021)
- LETTER FROM JOHN J. MORAN TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1937/07/24, TLS, TMsS (Box-folder 034-022)
  ENVELOPE, ENCLOSURE: MORAN'S AUTOBIOGRAPHY
- LETTER FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO JOHN J. MORAN 1937/07/27, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-023)
- LETTER FROM W.S. LEMON TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1937/07/31, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-024)
- ROLL OF HONOR, PARTICIPANTS IN YELLOW FEVER INVESTIGATIONS IN CUBA 1937/07, REPORT (Box-folder 034-025)
- LETTER FROM JOHN H. ANDRUS TO ALBERT E. TRUBY 1937/08/03, TLS (Box-folder 034-026)
- LETTER FROM JOHN J. MORAN TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1937/08/07, TLS (Box-folder 034-027)
- LETTER FROM JOHN H. ANDRUS TO JAMES H. LEWIS 1937/08/09, TLS (CC) (Box-folder 034-028)
- LETTER FROM ALTON P. TISDEL TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH "1937/08/09, 17", TLS (2) (Box-folder 034-029)
- LETTER FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO MRS. KIDWELL 1937/08/12, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-030)
- LETTER FROM JOHN J. MORAN TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1937/08/13, TLS (Box-folder 034-031)
  WITH EHVELOPE
- LETTER FROM JOHN H. ANDRUS TO JOHN J. MORAN 1937/08/16, TLS (Box-folder 034-032)
  FORWARDED THROUGH US ARMY VETERANS' BUREAU
- LETTER FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO ALTON P. TISDEL 1937/08/24, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-033)
- LETTER FROM JOHN H. ANDRUS TO JOHN J. MORAN 1937/08/30, TLS (Box-folder 034-034)
- LETTER FROM JOHN H. ANDRUS TO HARRY H. WOODRING 1937/08/30, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-035)
- LETTER FROM JOHN H. ANDRUS TO ALBERT E. TRUBY 1937/09/16, TLS (Box-folder 034-036)
- LETTER FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO JOHN J. MORAN 1937/09/22, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-037)
- LETTER FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO EDITOR OF THE ARMY REGISTER; FRANK C. BURNETT TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH "1937/09/22, 29", TLS (2) (Box-folder 034-038)
- LETTER FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO FRANK C. BURNETT 1937/10/06, TL (CC) (Box-folder 034-039)
- LETTER FROM PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO RALPH COOPER HUTCHISON "1937/10/14, 21", TL (CC) (2) (Box-folder 034-040)